RELAND BOYLE

Software Engineer

631-806-0019 reland.boyle@gmail.com • github.com/relandboyle New York, NY • linkedin.com/in/relandboyle

SUMMARY

Software engineer and generalist with 15+ years of professional experience in product development, mechanical design, project management, vendor relations, compliance, and customer success. Known for immediately becoming a subject-matter expert and a trusted source for technical information. Highly attuned to the needs of the Four Pillars: customer, company, team, and product.

SKILLS

Strong: JavaScript (ES6+) - React - Redux - Express.js - Node.js - Docker - Kubernetes - OAuth 2.0 - SQL/NoSQL Database • Material UI • webpack • CSS/Sass/Less • Jest • Enzyme • Prometheus • Electron • AWS • Linux • HTML Experienced: TypeScript - Python - Auth0 - Git/GitHub - Travis CI - Grafana - Google Cloud - Linode - Wordpress

Work Experience

DataCaliper - NetSuite Developer

November 2021 - March 2022

- Integrated SuiteScript 2.0 programs within SuiteCloud Developer Framework to customize NetSuite instances for 5 clients
- Produced Advanced PDF Templates, Workflows, and Formula Fields to reduce wait time and cognitive load by up to 60%
- Typically responded to client requests within 24 hours with effective, creative solutions and implemented within 5 business days

Rich Brilliant Willing - Assistant Director of Operations

January 2016 - August 2021

- Optimized processes across departments, automating repetitive tasks and implementing integrations between Oracle NetSuite ERP/CRM and 4 secondary platforms, working with tech such as NetSuite Workflows and SuiteScript Developer Framework
- Achieved 100% product compliance with relevant consumer product safety standards and internal performance standards
- Founded and managed RBW's Customer Success Team, hired CSR's, established metrics and service level agreements, reduced post-sale support cases from 15% to 5% of all sales while mentoring team members and generating internal tech wiki
- Routinely directed \$1M+ custom lighting projects through ideation, design, validation, manufacturing, delivery, and installation

Recent Projects

Drone Tools March 2022

- Developed a single-page React/TypeScript application to calculate propeller tip speed relative to local Mach 1
- Employed Netlify/AWS Lambda serverless functions to mask sensitive data in API calls from a frontend-only web application
- Doubled development velocity using React Hooks to manage state variables and synchronize user interface elements
- Introduced SCSS style sheets to achieve a responsive, mobile-friendly design that renders gracefully on screens of all sizes

Skills Grid February 2022

- Constructed a full-stack JavaScript web app with CRUD functionality using DOM manipulation, Express, and plain vanilla JS
- Authored modular LESS style sheets to provide consistent styling and transitions while writing more readable, maintainable CSS

Realized an idea put forth by Codesmith Chief Academic Officer Phillip Troutman to aid new graduates in the first job search

KR8S for Kubernetes November 2021

- Created a React/Electron single-page desktop application under the OS Labs tech accelerator to visualize and monitor Kubernetes cluster health and performance metrics, providing developers with real-time insight into the impact of changes made to the deployed application, streamlining development and reducing the need to review and respond to logs by up to 75%
- Automated deployment of a Dockerized multi-service React-based e-commerce application in a local Kubernetes cluster with pre-configured Prometheus server and over 10 Grafana dashboards for a 50% reduction in setup time for new Kubernetes users
- Leveraged Material UI, React Router, to rapidly construct accessible, production-quality navigation components, reducing the load on the KR8S development team and ensuring a highly consistent, high-quality user experience with minimal overhead

EDUCATION

 Triplebyte Engineering - Certificate Codesmith - Advanced Residency for Full Stack Engineers - Syllabus January 2022

Dassault Systemes - Certified SolidWorks Professional (Mechanical Design) - Certificate

November 2021 June 2020

ACHIEVEMENTS

Tech Talks - Sponsored by Single Sprout: <u>User Experience Best Practices</u>

October 2021 August 2021

Rich Brilliant Willing - Help Center

June 2021

CS Study Buddy Group - Host / Instructor